Ruth Strout McCandless Collection on Nyogen Senzaki, 1895-2007
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ruth Strout McCandless collection on Nyogen Senzaki
Bulk, 1940-1960
1895-2007
2296
UCLA Library Special Collections
11.2 linear feet (12 boxes, 3 cartons, 1 flat box, 1 oversize flat box, 1 roll storage box)
The Ruth Strout McCandless collection on Nyogen Senzaki contains materials related to Ruth McCandless' collaboration and association with Nyogen Senzaki and the American Zen Buddhist movement. Senzaki (1876-1958) was a Japanese Zen monk who left Japan for the United States in 1905. Senzaki lived in San Francisco and Los Angeles in the 1920s and 1930s, and played an important role in the formative years of the American Zen Buddhist movement. Ruth Strout McCandless was a South Pasadena resident who in 1941 became a disciple of Senzaki and later became a major scholar of Japanese Buddhism studies in the United States. The collection consists of correspondence, photographs, ephemera, books, business records, artwork, and textiles. Also included are original manuscripts by Senzaki with transcriptions and edits by Ruth McCandless, correspondence from Senzaki to McCandless during his incarceration in the Heart Mountain Relocation Center in Wyoming, a traditional Zen Buddhist Kesa robe, and a decorative scroll used in Senzaki's ministry.
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchase, 2015.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 8073484
Notes on Names Used
The name Kangetsu appears in these papers, presumably a Dharma name for Mrs. McCandless, since Senzaki praises her as one who "who can stich and mend" the "rips and rents" in his English.
The name Genpo Roshi is used to refer to Soen Nakagawa.
Biography/History
Nyogen Senzaki (1876–1958), born Aizo Senzaki, was a Zen Buddhist monk and one of the first Zen masters to come to the United States from Japan. He developed a following with his "floating zendo" model. Through his own writings, translations, and the work of his students including Samuel L. Lewis and Robert Aitken, he has been regarded as one of the 20th century's leading proponents of Zen Buddhism. His texts and translations, which aimed to make Zen Buddhist principles understandable and accessible, were a large influence in their popularity and adaption in Western culture.
Specifics of Senzaki's early life are unclear. He was raised in Northern Japan where he learned Chinese calligraphy and studied the Buddhist Sutras. Senzaki originally aspired to become a pediatrician, and attended Imperial University in Japan. Upon reading the Buddhist Tripitaka texts, he was inspired to become a Monk, and went on to study Zen under Soyen Shaku at the Rinzai School at the Engakuji Monastery in Kamakura. During his studies, Senzaki met Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki, a seminal Zen scholar and fellow student of Shaku. In 1905, Shaku travelled to America and brought Senzaki with him. He lived in San Francisco, working as a houseboy, a manager of a small hotel, and as an operator at the Chinese Telephone exchange. In 1922, Senzaki began to rent out a small hall to give lectures and host meditation groups. After moving to Los Angeles in the 1930s, he resided in Little Tokyo and gave semi-weekly talks and zazen. In the spring of 1942 he was incarcerated at the Heart Mountain Relocation Center in Wyoming, where he was held for 4 years. Following his release, Senzaki returned to Los Angeles and resumed his lectures, classes, and zazen. Senzaki passed away on May 7, 1958.
Ruth Strout McCandless (1909-1994) was Senzaki’s close collaborator and a major Western scholar on Zen Buddhism in Japan, particularly contributing to Zen Buddhist movements in California. While under the guidance of Soen Nakagawa at Ryutakuji, she became the first Western woman to stay at a Zen monastery. She was ordained as an Upasika of the Sangha under the mentorship of Senzaki in 1941.
McCandless was born in 1909 and grew up in the San Francisco Bay Area. She studied art, literature and science at Stanford University, where she graduated from in 1932. After school McCandless worked in the San Francisco Stock Exchange Institute. She later moved to Los Angeles where she worked in Hollywood in the publicity department for Samuel Goldwyn, and later as a secretary to screenwriter Reginald Berkeley. McCandless married her husband, John McCandless in 1932. She had two sons, Duncan and Keith McCandless. McCandless became interested in Zen Buddhism through her study of comparative religion, inspired by Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki's Essays in Zen Buddhism (1927). McCandless met Senzaki in the early 1940's and worked with him studying Zen and translating manuscripts. With Senzaki, McCandless co-authored Buddhism and Zen (1953), a book that provided an elementary introduction to Zen Buddhism aimed for Western audiences. She was also an editor of The Iron Flute (1961), a collection of ancient Zen koans. In 1961 McCandless and her husband divorced, prompting her to enroll in the Asian studies graduate department at Claremont Graduate University. She continued in the study of Zen Buddhism, and maintained friendships with many prominent figures in the Zen Buddhist community such as Soen Nakagawa, Eido Tai Shimano, and Ruth Fuller Sasaki. McCandless passed away on December 14, 1994 in San Mateo, California.
Scope and Content
This collection spans from 1895-2007 and consists of correspondence, photographs, books, and personal memorabilia pertaining to Ruth McCandless’ collaboration and association with Nyogen Senzaki and the American Zen Buddhist movement. The collection also contains manuscripts, lecture notes, translations, and periodicals. A particular strength of this collection is the material relating to the influence and rising popularity of Zen Buddhism on Western society in the 20th century. This is evidenced through Senzaki and McCandless' translations of historical texts, Senzaki's lecture notes from talks given in American universities, the formation of Zen Buddhist organizations in the United States, and publications that aimed to present Zen Buddhist teachings to Western audiences.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series, two of which have been further arranged in subseries. The series and subseries arrangement of the collection is as follows:
Series 1: Subject Files, 1930-2007
Series 2: Professional Materials, 1895-1971
Series 3: Publications, 1900-2006
Subseries 3.1: Printed Material, 1931-1988
Subseries 3.2: Monographs, 1900-2006
Series 4: Personal Materials, circa 1896-1990s
Subseries 4.1: Photographs, circa 1896-1984
Subseries 4.2: Correspondence and Memorabilia, circa 1930s-1990s
Related Material
Estelle Ishigo Papers, Japanese American Research Project (Yuji Ichioka) Collection of Material about Japanese in the United States (Collection 2010)
Akira Togawa Papers (Collection 1711)
McCandless, Ruth Strout -- Archives; Senzaki, Nyogen -- Archives; Zen Buddhism--United States.
Container List
- Series 1: Subject Files., 1930-2007.
  Scope and Content
  This series consists of subject files assembled by McCandless. Materials within the files include manuscripts, contracts, reviews, clippings, and publication material. This series also contains correspondence between McCandless and her acquaintances, such as Nyogen Senzaki, Soen Nakagawa, Ruth Sasaki, Eido T. Shimano, and Robert Aitken, as well as newsletters and material from the Zen Studies Society and The Honolulu Diamond Sangha. Materials, including business correspondence relating to The Iron Flute (1961) and Buddhism and Zen (1953) in which she collaborated with Senzaki are also represented.
  Organization and Arrangement
  Series 1 is organized alphabetically by subject title.
  - Buddhism and Zen materials., 1953-1992. (Box 1, Folder 1, Folder 2)
  - The Buddhist Society and Zen Studies Society: newsletters, publications., 1940-1994. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chanoyu: correspondence, writing., circa 1955-1960. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki: correspondence, publications, photographs., circa 1951-1964. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Duncan McCandless's correspondence., 1997-2007. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Eido Tai Shimano: correspondence, newsletters, publications., 1961-1994. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Honolulu Diamond Sangha Zen Buddhist Organization., 1961-1998. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Iron Flute materials., 1956-1988. (Box 1, Folder 9, Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kangetsu: Memoirs of Ruth Strout McCandless., April, 1944. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Main Currents in Modern Thought, featuring Ways of Experiencing Ch-an by Chang Chung-Yuan., January- February 1964. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mary Mc Aneny correspondence., 1968-1975. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - McCandless and Zen Buddhism: correspondence, writings, activities, clippings., circa 1941-1968. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nyogen Senzaki: correspondence, writing, poetry., 1930-1993. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publication correspondence and contracts., 1957-2000. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ruth Fuller Sasaki: correspondence, obituary, writing., 1933-1967. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Soen Nakagawa: correspondence, writing, artwork., 1948-1991.; These folders contain organic material. Use caution while handling. (Box 3, Folders 1-4)
  - Stanford University correspondence., 1949-1967. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Zen Buddhist writing., circa 1950s-1960s. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Professional Materials., 1895-1971.
  This series includes a collection of materials relating to the professional activities of McCandless and Senzaki. Material such as translated texts, manuscripts, lecture notes, and writing on Zen Buddhism are included. Works authored and translated by Senzaki are represented, as well as papers written by McCandless during her time at Claremont Graduate University. Other works by Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki and Soyen Shaku, who were influential figures in the work of both McCandless and Senzaki are also included. Other highlights include research for and annotated manuscripts of The Iron Flute (1961), in addition to McCandless' notes for Buddhism and Zen (1953).
  Series 2 is organized alphabetically by title.
  - Bodhi-Dharma's "Twofold Entrance to Zen", translated by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., circa 1950s. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Book of Equanimity, translated by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1944. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Buddhism and Zen by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth McCandless., 1952-1953. (Box 3, Folder 9, Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cautions on Meditation by Mumon Ekai, translated by Nyogen Senzaki., circa 1934. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Two-page translation of Mumon's Cautions on Meditation from the end of The Gateless Gate.
  - Compiled Zen Buddhist works: writing, poetry, notes., 1906-1952 (compiled circa 1950s). (Box 4, Folders 3-5)
    A collection of compiled readings. Includes texts by Soyen Shaku in addition to texts authored and translated by Nyogen Senzaki. Many of the readings are represented elsewhere in the collection.
  - Denshin-Ho-Yo by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., March 3-July 21, 1938. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Four-part lecture series given in 1938.
  - Emptiness by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1937. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Four Noble Truths, An Interpretation by Ruth McCandless., December 1962. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Term paper submitted by McCandless to Dr. Floyd H. Ross for her seminar in Buddhism at Claremont Graduate University
  - Fudo Zen and Japanese culture by Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki (photocopy)., 1941. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Gateless Gate by Mumon, translated by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1934-1939. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Gates of Zen and How to Enter Them: Lecture by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1937-1947. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Iron Flute Manuscript by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth McCandless., circa 1960. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Iron Flute: Nyogen Senzaki translations., 1939-1946. (Box 5, Folders 2-3)
  - Koans translated by Nyogen Senzaki., circa 1930s-1940s. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Kogo (zen poem) by Nyogen Senzaki., 1934-1971. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    A collection of Kogo (zen poems) by Senzaki written between 1934-1955. A selection of these poems have been published in Like a Dream, Like a Fantasy (1978), a compilation of Senzaki's Zen teachings and translations edited by Eido Tai Shimano. The poems are divided chronologically into three periods. 1. Poems prior to incarceration: Mostly written to commemorate key dates on the Zen calender but also to mark occasions such as Dwight Goddard's death or a memorial for Lafcadio Hearn. 2. Poems during incarceration at Heart Mountain: Included are poems written on Heart Mountain stationery, as well as poems written to Kangetsu (McCandless). 3. Poems after release from Heart Mountain: Included are twelve poems written in Japanese and a one-page translation. The Japanese poems seem to have been placed here mistakenly; they belong chronologically but are out of place in a section of specifically Chinese poems. Many of the Japanese poems are addressed to McCandless.
  - Last Day of Buddha from "The Splendour of Asia": A sutra read at Soto Zen Temple (photocopy)., February 14th, 1932. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Lessons in Meditation by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1945-1946. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    "Lessons in Mediation," part I: two page translation of a two sentence text presumably by Keizan Zenji with commentary, presumably by Senzaki. "Lesson in Zazen," parts II and III: three pages, presumably a continuation of the preceding with some longhand corrections.
  - Memorandum: Ruth McCandless's letter to Soen San (photocopy)., circa 1940s-1960s. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Message from a Pure Land: Ruth McCandless's letters to Nyogen Senzaki., 1942-1945. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Letters in this file were written to Senzaki while he was incarcerated at the Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
  - Mt. Koya and Shingon teaching by Ronald Lane Latimer (photocopy)., circa 1930s. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Muhan's Fragmentary Notes, translated by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1946. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Nineteen pages. A translation of a 1666 text by Shido Muhan, with notes by Senzaki. A selection of the text is included in Zen Flesh, Zen Bones (1957).
  - Notes on Buddhism and Zen by Nyogen Senzaki, compiled and edited by Ruth McCandless., February, 1950. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Nyogen Senzaki lecture notes., circa 1930s-1950s. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Contains notes from Senzaki's lectures including "Some Problems of Buddhism", "Law of Cause and Effect", and "The Four Methods of Meditation".
  - Outline of the Diamond Sutra by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., May 23, 1937. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Poetry by Nyogen Senzaki, Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki, and Soyen Shaku (photocopy)., 1906. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Practice of Dhyana by Soyen Shaku (photocopy)., 1906. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Published in Sermons of a Buddhist Abbot (1913), as well as Zen for Americans (1987).
  - The Sages of the East by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1937. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    A reading and response to an article by Sufi master Inayat Khan. Lecture given in three parts in 1937.
  - Sermons of a Buddhist Abbot by Soyen Shaku, translated by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki (copy)., 1906. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Seven Treasures lecture (photocopy)., May 28-June 11, 1935. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Fourteen-page lecture in three parts, given in 1935.
  - Shodoka by Yoka Daishi, translated by Nyogen Senzaki and Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki (photocopy)., 1936-1937. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Shortcut to Zazen by Kawajiri Hogin, translated by Nyogen Senzaki., 1944. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Should I Say My Last Words by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., August 12, 1939. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Simple Talks on the Simple Life: A translation of Sai-kon-dan by Ko-ji-sei, lecture notes by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., February 1, 1938. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sound of One Hand Clapping by Inzan School, translated by Nyogen Senzaki., April 9, 1947. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Soyen Shaku and Nyogen Senzaki: writing, poetry, correspondence., 1895-1954. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Soyen Shaku Biography by Nyogen Senzaki., 1951. (Box 6, Folders 14-15)
    Includes a speech by Senzaki given in commemoration of Soyen Shaku on "Roshi Day".
  - Speaking materials by Nyogen Senzaki., 1932-1942. (Box 7, Folders 1-2)
    Includes the manuscript for The Gateless Gate (1934) with translation and commentary by Nyogen Senzaki, as delivered in class in 1939. The translation and introduction were published (with Paul Reps) in 1934 and remain in print in Zen Flesh, Zen Bones (1957). Other texts include The Gates of Zen and How to Enter Them, Turning the Wheel of Dharma, and other lecture and speech notes for Senzaki's talks on Buddhism and meditation.
  - Story of Rengetsu (photocopy)., circa 1930s. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Suggestions for Zen Students by Zen Getsu (photocopy)., 1934-1938. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    One-page translation of a text by Zen-getsu. Previously published in both Zen Flesh, Zen Bones (1957), pp. 87-88, and Buddhism and Zen (1953), pp. 70-71.
  - The Sutra of Forty Two Chapters (photocopy)., 1906. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    "The Sutra of Forty Two Chapters": appears to be D.T. Suzuki's translation with less footnotes as it was published in Soyen Shaku's, Sermons of a Buddhist Abbot (1913) and Reprinted by Dorset Press in 1987 under the title Zen for Americans.
  - Sutra Spoken by the Sixth Patriarch, Wei Lang, on the High Seat of the Gem of Law., March 1930. (Box 7, Folders 6-7)
    Contains one bound manuscript.
  - Tao Teh King by A.L. Kitselmann II., 1936. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Ten Bulls: A Chinese Classic by Kwaku-An, translated by Nyogen Senzaki (photocopy)., 1935. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Translation of The Ten Oxherding Pictures, a well-know Buddhist teaching aimed to illustrate the stages of practice towards enlightenment. This text remains in print in pp. 163-187 of Zen Flesh, Zen Bones (1957), although without Senzaki's preface given here.
  - Three Wheels: lecture notes (photocopy)., 1932. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Tuesday talk: Nyogen Senzaki's lecture notes on Buddhism, sorrow, nirvana (photocopy)., November 21, 1933. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Writings on Buddhism and meditation (photocopy)., 1934, undated. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Includes "Questions About Meditation", "A Message From Tibetan Buddhists", "How to Maintain our Sangha" and "The Four Methods of Meditation".
  - Zenga Japanese Zen Painting by Ruth McCandless., April 1963. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Term paper submitted by McCandless to Dr. Jon C. Covell for her course in Japanese Art History at Claremont Graduate University.
- Series 3: Publications., 1900-2006.
  This series includes a wide range of monographs, pamphlets, and booklets collected by Ruth McCandless. They are reflective of her interests in Japanese history and Buddhism, in addition to being illustrative of texts that aimed to introduce Zen Buddhist teachings to a Western audience. Also represented are publications distributed by organizations such as The First Zen Institute of America, The Zen Studies Society, and The Buddhist Lodge, London. Texts by prominent figures in the American Zen movement including Ruth Fuller Sasaki, Eido Tai Shimano, Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki, and Robert Aitken are also represented.
  Series 3 is organized into subseries, which are subsequently organized alphabetically by title.
  - Subseries 3.1: Printed Material., 1931-1988.
    This subseries contains printed publications that provide basic knowledge of Japanese Buddhism and culture. It includes Buddhist manuals, the Zen Studies Society’s pamphlets, and a number of volumes of The Tourist Library, a series of pamphlets distributed by the Board of Tourist Industry Japanese Government Railways from 1934-1942. Many of the materials feature illustrations, drawings, and photographs.
    Subseries 3.1 is organized alphabetically by title.
    - Antenatal Training., circa 1940s. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Book of Tea by Okakura-Kakuzo., 1939. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - A Brief Glossary of Buddhist Terms by the Buddhist Lodge, London., 1931. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Buddhist Philosophy and Its Effects on the Life and Thought of the Japanese People by Kokusai Bunka Shinkokai., 1936. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Eranos lectures: The Interior and Exterior in Zen Buddhism by Toshihiko Izutsu., 1975. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The First Zen Institute of America in Japan at Ryosen-an Daitokuji., 1959. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Gateless Gate translated by Nyogen Senzaki and Saladin Reps., 1934. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Inshi., circa 1940s-1960s. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Inward Light edited by Elined Kotschnig., 1953. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Features writing by Nyogen Senzaki and Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki.
    - L'Eveil suprême: Bases pratiques du Ch'an, du Zen et de la pensée de Krishnamurti by Robert Linssen., 1958. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Les dix tableaux du domestiquage de la vache by Jean Herbert., 1960. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - The Practice of Zen: article review by Paul Wienpahl., 1963. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Rinzai Zen Study For Foreigners in Japan by Ruth Fuller Sasaki., 1960. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Tea Cult of Japan by Yasunosuke Fukukita., 1955. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Ten Bulls of Zen a Chinese Classic translated by Nyogen Senzaki and Saladin Reps., 1935. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Tourist Library Volume 1: Tea Cult of Japan by Yasunosuke Fukukita., 1935. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Tourist Library Volume 2: Japanese Noh Plays by Toyoichiro Nogami., 1935. (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Two Copies, One with Annotations.
    - Tourist Library Volume 4: Japanese Gardens by Matunosukke Tatui., 1938. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Tourist Library Volume 5: Hiroshige and Japanese Landscapes by Yone Noguchi., 1934. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Tourist Library Volume 7: Japanese Architecture by Hideto Kishida., 1935. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Tourist Library Volume 8: What is Shinto? by Genchi Kato., 1935. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Tourist Library Volume 9: Castles in Japan by N. Orui., 1935. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Tourist Library Volume 10: Hot Springs in Japan by Koichi Fujinami., 1936. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Tourist Library Volume 11: Floral Art of Japan by Issotei Nishikawa., 1936. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Tourist Library Volume 12: Children's Days in Japan by Tamotsu Iwado., 1936. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Tourist Library Volume 15: Japanese Music by Katsumi Sunaga., 1936. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Tourist Library Volume 16: Judo (Jujutsu) by Jigoro Kano., 1937. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Tourist Library Volume 17: Family Life in Japan by Shunkichi Akimoto., 1937. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tourist Library Volume 20: Floral Calendar of Japan by T. Makino and Genziro Oka., 1938. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tourist Library Volume 21: Japanese Buddhism by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1938. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tourist Library Volume 23: Kabuki Drama by Syutaro Miyake., 1938. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tourist Library Volume 31: Japan's Ancient Armour by Hatiro Yamagami., 1940. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Tourist Library Volume 33: Japanese Proverbs by Otoo Huzii., 1940. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Tourist Library Volume 34: Sumo-Japanese Wrestling by Kozon Hikoyama., 1940. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Wei Shih Er Shih Lun: The Treatise in Twenty Stanzas on Reprentation-only, American Oriental Series Volume 18, Monograph., 1938. (Box 9, Folder 5)